A lot of people in Asia are so
disappointed in Ethereum. I think a lot
of people globally are disappointed in
ETH and I I think that that's true. I
don't think ETH is going anywhere. I
think ETH has a messaging problem. I
can't really imagine our space without
Ethereum. We want Ethereum to be the
number two market cap, right? Well, do
we number two slot to be open to
competition? I think that that would be
a really interesting idea. I mean among
other things I think we can't forget how
Salana kind of came back from the dead
post FTX. So I think people who are
saying like ETH is down and out for the
count are very much forgetting what
we've seen other chains come back to to
do. I think one of the things our sector
as a whole um suffers from is I'm pretty
comfortable with what I see as the macro
levers that are being pulled. Um and I
think that there's a lot of effort being
put into sort of frontloading the pain
and sort of stepping on everything at
once. I think for it to work, uh, the
fear has to be real. I'm already scared.
Right. There you There you go. So, it's
working.
[Music]
We're joined today by Blue Macharelli,
head of digital assets at Troll Price.
We'll be talking about crypto
institutional trading. Welcome to the
show. Thank you. Thank you for having
me. I'm David Lynn. I'm Bonnie from
Bonnie Blockchain. And uh, great to have
you. Let's start with your background.
You were institutional trafi trading, TD
Securities, Lehman. You're doing
credits, you were at the credits desk,
derivatives desk, and now you're doing
what exactly? So, I spent 20 years in
emerging market debt, uh, Lehman, uh,
Elliot, uh, and then I moved into crypto
full-time in, uh, end of 2017. I like to
joke I'm actually only 25 years old.
I've just been in crypto for eight
years, right? Okay. um and ran a market
neutral um crypto fund for the first
four years and then joined Tro to head
up digital assets in 2022. What was the
major first culture shock that you
experienced going from you know large
institutional trafi to digital assets
presumably liquidity is one difference
but what else? Liquidity is one
difference. Um I think another one is um
especially from a market neutral um
highfrequency perspective you're sort of
plugging directly into a retail exchange
and none of them are the same. So it's
not the same as okay now we're plugging
into you know sort of the New York Stock
Exchange we only have to face one. It's
we are simultaneously plugging into and
interfacing with like eight or 10
different exchanges all of which are
structured built different architecture
everything looks different so it's
highly customized 2017 was relatively
early in the crypto bull cycle I mean
arbitrage opportunities must have been
everywhere I mean I yeah they were
significant I think a lot of those
arbitrage opportunities have you know
sort of since diminished I think one of
the things that people who were
interested in arbitrage recognizes that
um at least at that point 2017
2018 Bitcoin was the only asset or
commodity right that is truly 100%
fungeible i.e. trades exact same thing
trades in different places
simultaneously at different prices. So
wheat isn't like that. Oil isn't
actually like that. Even onshore,
offshore, ADR or GDR sort of trading
isn't truly funible. Um and so it
presents a really interesting true
arbitrage which is really really rare to
find. Yeah, that's how Alama Research
made their money. But that's a topic for
different for a long time. It was very
confusing how they just kept performing
so well and it's like oh now now it
makes sense. Anyway, we also want to
talk about Ethereum. Um a lot of people
in Asia are so disappointed in Ethereum.
Yeah, I think um I think a lot of people
globally are disappointed in ETH and I I
think that that's true. Um I don't think
um I don't think ETH is going anywhere.
I think ETH has a messaging problem. Um,
and I think that uh there's there are
indications that they are aware of it,
right? And you see it at the Ethereum
Foundation sort of they're going through
a sort of crisis of conscious and and
they're going to come out the other
side. Um, but I think that the
combination of the true
decentralization, the security, the
programmability, I think that ETH will,
you know, will come through this. Um, I
think that we're destined to live in a
multi-chain, multi-token world, and I
think there's a role for ETH there. Um,
I think that, uh, I can't really imagine
our space without Ethereum. But is that
good enough? We want Ethereum to be the
number two market cap, right? Well, do
we? Right. I think that that's a good
question, right? I think that that I
think it would be healthy for our space
for that number two slot to be open to
competition. And I think that that would
be a really interesting idea.
Um I I think that um so I know that
people tend to think of sort of it's
like the ETH versus Salana like back and
forth. I mean among other things I think
we can't forget how Salana kind of came
back from the dead post FTX. So I think
people who are saying like ETH is down
and out for the count are very much
forgetting what we've seen other chains
come back to to do. Um, I think that
Avalanche is um I think it's a a chain
that gets an incredible amount of
traction among institutions. I think it
doesn't get the same attention from, you
know, crypto, Twitter, and retail.
Um, I think that's a really good
question. I I don't know why that is. Um
but I think that it's again uh with the
customization of L1's sort of the
ability to do a bespoke L1 um achieve
finality quickly uh and there there are
a number of features which make it
something that many institutions are
comfortable operating on. If you look at
sort of the large institutions and where
they've done, you know, their proof of
concept for different types of onchain
trading, you know, Avalanche is a leader
in that space and I think that it kind
of goes unrecognized a little bit um
among the dungeons in the What about
Ripple XRP?
So Ripple is an interesting one. I think
um we have I think that I'm very
interested to see where Ripple heads in
sort of its next iteration, right? I
think um I think that they are focused
on what comes next and I think I don't
feel like I have as clear an idea of
what comes next for them as as I think I
would like to. So Salana memecoin was
the thing and it died kind of sort of
disappeared. Um now what like what's
going to affect Salana price? So I yeah
I think we saw um we saw this sort of
very much a round trip based on the
memecoin frenzy with Salana. Um I think
so I think that there's like a whole
defense of memecoins that I could give
which is always a hot topic at Tro
people are very fascinated to hear that
but um but I think that we would not see
deepen being built on Salana the way
that it is if we hadn't seen the network
pushed tested in terms of throughput in
terms of the ability to transact
incredibly large volumes um of what is
effectively like a low value item. You
can't you can't use it for proof of
coverage or proof of mapping or or any
of those things um until it can handle
huge throughput at very very low
transaction prices. And so so deep you
think is a big topic. It was popular
last year. Yes, it was. But this year it
kind of nobody's talking about it
anymore.
So I think that one of the reasons I
really like deepen is I think it makes
our entire industry much more accessible
to people. I right so when I'm not
wearing my crypto digital assets hat
when I am like at school pickup and
people are like okay but what does the
blockchain do and it's like deepen
allows you to explain that. It's like
this is sort of one of the first places
that I think a much broader audience can
begin to access this concept of web 3
which is users can also be owners and
they can be operators right so you'd be
amazed like the number of like preschool
moms that I've like signed up for helium
for example right um I want to circle
back to Ethereum so you said they have a
messaging problem which means maybe the
foundation did not deliver their message
very clearly and also people are
wondering if the business model favors
layer 2 but not Ethereum itself but that
is not really fixable in a short period
of
time. So I think I think one of the
things that this is probably not a
popular view I think one of the things
our sector as a whole um suffers from is
a very short-term view of things. Yes.
Yes. Okay. Uh and so I
think one of the things that exists in
our sector that does not exist in other
traditional assets is the ability to
change and iterate on elements of the
economics of the project over time,
right? And I think that we often don't
give, you know, um protocols um or
projects the time and the space to do
that. Um we're as an industry we tend to
be pretty quick to write things off. Um
so and I think that that's important. I
think that we need to sort of let those
changes take place but sometimes if you
are too patient the project just
disappears.
Yes. Oh, I mean I it's it is it's a
fastmoving technology and things
um things sort of have this um right to
use like an options concept things have
a time decay as soon as they come on
chain right um and we have a much higher
sort of discount rate than any other
industry. Okay. Um going back to
markets. So we were talking about
Salana. Here's a chart of while you guys
were chatting I put this up ETH plus
Salana market cap. Uh this is Bitcoin.
So two-part question. one, why the
underperformance or the Bitcoin
dominance um outperformance rather? And
two, if you just take a look at Salana
versus BTC, there's still a close
correlation. Is that still the future of
altcoins, which is tracking Bitcoin?
Yeah. So I think um we have to remember
like how new our entire industry is and
I think that one of the things that you
have seen happen initially with the ETPs
right is that we have seen onboarding of
retail people who were not operating on
chain natively and that process started
with Bitcoin and to a much lesser extent
Ethereum. I think that people um were
faster to understand the narrative
around Bitcoin. Um and I think that you
have to some degree a schism between
sort of tokens that can be traded
natively um and then tokens or bitcoin
which can be traded both natively but
you can also invest in if you are not
operating on chain right and I think
that that narrative that sort of
evolution is going to be a really
dominant theme over the next presumably
year is that there's a schism between
what an institutional investor or your
average retail investor on the street
with like a you know a brokerage account
can invest in versus somebody who's
operating on chain and that's going to
take time right
you are a mom yes what is wrong with the
financial education nowadays
um that's a really good question I think
that we don't prepare our children um to
consider the time value of money I think
that we don't um incentivize them to
save and to invest. So my kids have been
investing since they were
5 years old. 5 years old. So the first
thing that we did with them was I don't
know if you remember Constitution Dow.
So we like we watched like the you know
what is it American treasure like the
national treasure movie and like we
looked at the constitution then we went
on chain used juice box like contributed
to the constitution now and they were
like oh my god we got this like we're
participating in trying to buy the
constitution right and it made sense to
them um and and so we have brought our
children you know sort of into the world
of finance using like largely onchain
tools because it makes sense for them
And it works for them. Gaming. Do they
have to work for the fund? Yes, they do.
How? Um, so we have them do chores
around the house. There's like a reward
system. Like there's a reward system
related to homework and studying and,
you know, not beating up your siblings
and not making me, things like that. How
do you feel about the video game play to
earn model? Would you would you
encourage your kids to play like Call of
Duty or whatever, but they like, you
know, beat the quest, they get crypto.
Yeah. So, here's and here's like they
earn money. They they do. Um I am
obviously I'm like a middle-aged mom of
three. I am like not the target market
for gaming. And so I will often hand
things off to like my 10-year-old now
10-year-old son and say, "Okay, like
let's like road test it. What do you
think?" Um something that never made any
sense to me was the like play to earn
model. I was like, I just I just don't
get how that is like an economic model
for a game that makes sense over any
sort of long-term period. What I do
recognize as the person who pays for
everything in FIFA in like the amount if
if Robux was like a real currency, like
you know, we would be um yeah, we're
Robux Robux rich, cash poor, right? So,
um, the idea of property ownership in
games makes absolute sense to me. I was
like, that I can get behind, especially
because I'm the one who's buying all of
the things. So, the idea that they can
sort of engage in economic activity,
that there are ownership rights that can
transfer, I think is absolutely
brilliant. And I think that is the piece
that makes sense to me in terms of of
GameFi. Yeah. Okay. Gamefy is really
just DeFi wrapped in a different form.
Yeah. I just I I'm I just Yeah, I get
it. I've struggled with it. Have you
ever played uh games that earn you
crypto? Yeah. Yeah. I used to make a lot
of money. I was like, I'm so rich and I
don't sell and then I'm down like 100%.
Right. Like Yeah. After two months. But
we've all had that experience of
something in crypto, right? So, um I
think we've all been be burned by
something. Yeah. Yeah. It's like really
have you have you lived if you haven't
been? um life advice for your younger
self getting into institutional finance
and trading. Um you know not a lot of
women in the big banks especially on
institutional trading and sales and
trading side. Um so there are I like to
joke that my love language is charts.
So, um there is a lot of evidence that
suggests that when it comes to actually
trading and investing that women often
make stronger traders and investors um
they don't churn as much. So, often
times like there's a there's a study out
of the St. Louis Fed if you're
interested. I can attest to that. I used
to churn all the time. I lost all my
money. Yeah. So like like yeah if you
turn you like are always kind of chasing
and and I think um it's about do your
homework until you have that conviction
and understand what your stop loss is
but also understand like catalysts that
are coming you know coming down the pike
and and what is happening but have
conviction that you've done your
homework like trust yourself that you
have done the work to sort of feel
comfortable in your position and and
then you know that's how you wear rins
do I ever FOMO
I mean, sometimes I'm also like I'm like
a middle-aged mom of three. Like the my
like I feel like my FOMO days are kind
of like pretty far behind me. Um but uh
but like I Yeah, I think that it's
important for one of the things that's
important for me is like to still get
out there and do things like you know
trade fartcoin pa. Are there some common
mistakes that are there common mistakes
that institutional and retail traders
alike
make in terms of principles their their
view on positioning and stuff like that?
I mean I think um I would say that the
number one what I think of as the number
one risk often times is
aligning aligning your investment thesis
and investment horizon with your
liquidity. Right? So um you know uh
spreads like ultimately always recurge
but you know can you stay you know can
you stay liquid long enough. So I think
that really understanding the difference
between what is my investment horizon,
where do I think the catalysts are, what
is my stop loss versus what is, you
know, what is my liquidity positioning?
Um, and I think that's something we see
frequently in the highly leveraged world
of crypto. Often times, let's say we
have an audience um, early 30s with 100K
sitting on the sideline. What would you
invest in right now? Anything. It
doesn't have to be crypto. Um, so I mean
I think I would I would definitely do an
allocation um to Bitcoin. I I think um I
think that uh what we're what we've seen
in equity markets recently is
potentially like a an entry point. I
think um I'm pretty
comfortable with what I see as the macro
levers that are being pulled. Um, and I
think that there's a lot of effort being
put into sort of frontloading the pain
and sort of stepping on everything at
once. Uh,
and and it makes sense to me. Um, so I
think that US equities I'm not saying
we're not calling a local bottom, but I
I think that um I'm pretty sanguin about
US equity risk here over a longer term
period. And I would
um more than anything else, I would sort
of divide it into, you know, 90%
long-term assets, investments that I'm
going to sit with that I'm going to
hold. And I think that, you know, my
early 30s, like, you know, 10%, 15% out
there to play with and learn is really
important. That was for 100K. Let's up
the ante. Let's make that 100 million.
Would that change? Would that answer
change?
Um, I think that 100 million I'm I'm
much more willing to take I'm much more
willing to take alternative asset risk
where there's a lockup. I'm willing to
have a much longer investment time
horizon. Um, and so I think that that
means I can have a higher risk tolerance
and risk profile. Um, my kids have Roth
IR like custodial Roth IAS. So obviously
my children are invested in their
custodial Roth IAS quite differently
than I'm invested in mine and you know
sort of as a middle-aged mom, right? So
they have a risk tolerance at 5 years
old that's quite different from right
what you should have in as a as an adult
with dependence. Okay, last question for
me. I'll pass it over to Bonnie and
finish up. Um you said you're relatively
sanguin on US equities. I mean the
markets have been jittery. So you know
why why that viewpoint? What makes me
comfortable? Um I think it's because I
come from a macro an em and a fixed
income point of view. Um I think we have
seen if you are if from a policy
perspective you wanted to engineer a
lower end back end of the curve. You did
not want to cut rates and risk a
resurgence of inflation. you wanted to
sort of frontload what are often
perceived to be multiple elements of a
structural adjustment program. This is
how you would do that. Um I think I
think I described it to my kids as it's
like we've put ourselves on a crash
diet, but like we've put ourselves on
the diet, right? So it's a lot of these
elements are still within our control.
Um and I think
that it's a very aggressive set of
policies meant to frontload and sort of
engineer those adjustments so that um so
that things can return to growth and
there's sort of larger space for the
private sector going forward right
without higher inflation without you
know the back end of the curve like
bouncing way up. But I think everyone's
wondering how long is this pain going to
last, right? When we talk about short
term, is it half a year, 3 months? What
are we talking about? Um, I think I
think we don't know.
Um, I think for it to work, uh, the fear
has to be real like for for this I'm
already scared. Right. There you there
you go. So, it's working, right? So the
faster we're all scared, the faster like
the the structural adjustment is sort of
um taking hold and and coming in. But um
but we also we need to have like
inflation expectations anchored firmly.
And I think that's a really key in my
mind that would be a key indicator to
watch is inflation expectations and and
firming up of those expectations.
Excellent. Well, let's wrap it up here.
Thank you very much. Thanks for having
me. Thank you.